{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A constructor that accepts __________ parameters is called the default constructor.", "opta": "one", "optb": "two", "optc": "no", "optd": "three", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens when a class with parameterized constructors and having no default constructor is used in a program and we create an object that needs a zero-argument constructor?", "opta": "Compile-time error.", "optb": "Preprocessing error.", "optc": "Runtime error.", "optd": "Runtime exception.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Can a class have virtual destructor?", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Destructor has the same name as the constructor and it is preceded by ______ .", "opta": "!", "optb": "?", "optc": "~", "optd": "$", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For automatic objects, constructors and destructors are called each time the objects", "opta": "enter and leave scope", "optb": "inherit parent class", "optc": "are constructed", "optd": "are destroyed", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which constructor function is designed to copy objects of the same class type?", "opta": "Create constructor", "optb": "Object constructor", "optc": "Dynamic constructor", "optd": "Copy constructor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Constructor has the same name as that of the class.", "optb": "Destructor has the same name as that of the class with a tilde symbol at the beginning.", "optc": "Both A and B.", "optd": "Destructor has the same name as the first member function of the class.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect?", "opta": "Constructor is a member function of the class.", "optb": "The compiler always provides a zero argument constructor.", "optc": "It is necessary that a constructor in a class should always be public.", "optd": "Both B and C.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When are the Global objects destroyed?", "opta": "When the control comes out of the block in which they are being used.", "optb": "When the program terminates.", "optc": "When the control comes out of the function in which they are being used.", "optd": "As soon as local objects die.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Copy constructor must receive its arguments by __________ .", "opta": "either pass-by-value or pass-by-reference", "optb": "only pass-by-value", "optc": "only pass-by-reference", "optd": "only pass by address", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A function with the same name as the class, but preceded with a tilde character (~) is called __________ of that class.", "opta": "constructor", "optb": "destructor", "optc": "function", "optd": "object", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A union that has no constructor can be initialized with another union of __________ type.", "opta": "different", "optb": "same", "optc": "virtual", "optd": "class", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gets called when an object goes out of scope?", "opta": "constructor", "optb": "destructor", "optc": "main", "optd": "virtual function", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Destructor destroys only integer data members of the object.", "optb": "Destructor destroys only float data members of the object.", "optc": "Destructor destroys only pointer data members of the object.", "optd": "Destructor destroys the complete object.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ used to make a copy of one class object from another class object of the same class type.", "opta": "constructor", "optb": "copy constructor", "optc": "destructor", "optd": "default constructor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Constructors __________ to allow different approaches of object construction.", "opta": "cannot overloaded", "optb": "can be overloaded", "optc": "can be called", "optd": "can be nested", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "A destructor has the same name as the class in which it is present.", "optb": "A destructor has a different name than the class in which it is present.", "optc": "A destructor always returns an integer.", "optd": "A destructor can be overloaded.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following cannot be declared as virtual?", "opta": "Constructor", "optb": "Destructor", "optc": "Data Members", "optd": "Both A and C", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the copy constructor receives its arguments by value, the copy constructor would", "opta": "call one-argument constructor of the class", "optb": "work without any problem", "optc": "call itself recursively", "optd": "call zero-argument constructor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are NOT provided by the compiler by default?", "opta": "Zero-argument Constructor", "optb": "Destructor", "optc": "Copy Constructor", "optd": "Copy Destructor", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is a __________ error to pass arguments to a destructor.", "opta": "logical", "optb": "virtual", "optc": "syntax", "optd": "linker", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the programmer does not explicitly provide a destructor, then which of the following creates an empty destructor?", "opta": "Preprocessor", "optb": "Compiler", "optc": "Linker", "optd": "main() function", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A __________ is a constructor that either has no parameters, or if it has parameters, all the parameters have default values.", "opta": "default constructor", "optb": "copy constructor", "optc": "Both A and B", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many default constructors per class are possible?", "opta": "Only one", "optb": "Two", "optc": "Three", "optd": "Unlimited", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct about destructors?", "opta": "A destructor has void return type.", "optb": "A destructor has integer return type.", "optc": "A destructor has no return type.", "optd": "A destructors return type is always same as that of main().", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "A constructor has the same name as the class in which it is present.", "optb": "A constructor has a different name than the class in which it is present.", "optc": "A constructor always returns an integer.", "optd": "A constructor cannot be overloaded.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following implicitly creates a default constructor when the programmer does not explicitly define at least one constructor for a class?", "opta": "Preprocessor", "optb": "Linker", "optc": "Loader", "optd": "Compiler", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A destructor takes __________ arguments.", "opta": "one", "optb": "two", "optc": "three", "optd": "no", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Destructor calls are made in which order of the corresponding constructor calls?", "opta": "Reverse order", "optb": "Forward order", "optc": "Depends on how the object is constructed", "optd": "Depends on how many objects are constructed", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following never requires any arguments?", "opta": "Member function", "optb": "Friend function", "optc": "Default constructor", "optd": "const function", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A class's __________ is called when an object is destroyed.", "opta": "constructor", "optb": "destructor", "optc": "assignment function", "optd": "copy constructor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Destructors __________ for automatic objects if the program terminates with a call to function exit or function abort.", "opta": "are called", "optb": "are inherited", "optc": "are not called", "optd": "are created", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "A constructor of a derived class can access any public and protected member of the base class.", "optb": "Constructor cannot be inherited but the derived class can call them.", "optc": "A constructor of a derived class cannot access any public and protected member of the base class.", "optd": "Both A and B.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements are correct?", "opta": "Constructor is always called explicitly.", "optb": "Constructor is called either implicitly or explicitly, whereas destructor is always called implicitly.", "optc": "Destructor is always called explicitly.", "optd": "Constructor and destructor functions are not called at all as they are always inline.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many times a constructor is called in the life-time of an object?", "opta": "Only once", "optb": "Twice", "optc": "Thrice", "optd": "Depends on the way of creation of object", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gets called when an object is being created?", "opta": "constructor", "optb": "virtual function", "optc": "destructor", "optd": "main", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To ensure that every object in the array receives a destructor call, always delete memory allocated as an array with operator __________ .", "opta": "destructor", "optb": "delete", "optc": "delete[]", "optd": "kill[]", "opte": "free[]", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct about constructors?", "opta": "A constructor has a return type.", "optb": "A constructor cannot contain a function call.", "optc": "A constructor has no return type.", "optd": "A constructor has a void return type.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct whenever an object goes out of scope?", "opta": "The default constructor of the object is called.", "optb": "The parameterized destructor is called.", "optc": "The default destructor of the object is called.", "optd": "None of the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}